scuba.com 2018-01-02

# scuba.com Security and Privacy

This privacy notice discloses the privacy practices for www.scuba.com. This privacy notice applies solely to information collected by this website, except where stated otherwise. It will notify you of the following:

  * What information we collect;
  * With whom it is shared;
  * How it can be corrected;
  * How it is secured;
  * How policy changes will be communicated; and
  * How to address concerns over misuse of personal data.

### Information Collection, Use, and Sharing 

We are the sole owners of the information collected on this site. We only have access to/collect information that you voluntarily give us via email or other direct contact from you. We will not sell or rent this information to anyone.

We will use your information to respond to you, regarding the reason you contacted us. We will not share your information with any third party outside of our organization, other than as necessary to fulfill your request, e.g., to ship an order.

Unless you ask us not to, we may contact you via email in the future to tell you about specials, new products or services, or changes to this privacy policy.

### Your Access to and Control Over Information 

You may opt out of any future contacts from us at any time. You can do the following at any time by contacting us via the email address or phone number provided on our website:

  * See what data we have about you, if any.
  * Change/correct any data we have about you.
  * Have us delete any data we have about you.
  * Express any concern you have about our use of your data.

### Security 

We take precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and offline.

Wherever we collect sensitive information (such as credit card data), that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. You can verify this by looking for a closed lock icon at the bottom of your web browser, or looking for "https" at the beginning of the address of the web page.

While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (e.g, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The computers/servers on which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.

### Notification of Changes

Whenever material changes are made to this policy a revised privacy policy will be placed on this website. 

If you feel that we are not abiding by this privacy policy, you should contact us immediately using the contact information provided on this website. 

* * *

## Secure Shopping

Orders placed on our site are encrypted using SSL technology, so rest assured that your transactions are protected. With SSL implemented on both the client and server, information sent via the Internet can be trusted to arrive privately and unaltered to our server only. In order for SSL security to work, you must use an SSL-enabled browser, such as version 3 or later of Microsoft Internet Explorer or Netscape Navigator. 

* * *

##  FAQ's

**Q: What personally identifiable information is collected and how is it used?**  
**A:** We capture only the infomation necessary to complete your order, such as Billing Address and Shipping Address. 

**Q: What are cookies and how are they used?**   
**A:** Cookies are files that are stored on your local computer usually used to enhance your web experience. There are two types of information stored in your cookies: 

  * Your order number(s).  

  * Your customer number(s), which is encrypted.   
No credit card information or personal information is stored in cookies.

**Q: What navigational information is collected and how is it used?**  
**A:** We capture only the URL which referred you to our site, such as Yahoo!.

**Q: Can customers modify their personal information given?**  
**A:** Our customers can make changes to their personal information given on each order.

**Q: How will my email be used?  
****A:** Customers subscribing to our free newsletter will receive product specials only available to our email subscribers. They will also receive emails to write reviews for the products they have purchased and win prizes.

**Q: How do users opt out of receiving any marketing material?  
A: **Customers who wish not to recieve any marketing materials need can change their preference by logging into My Account at any time or to going to our Email List Removal Page. Customers can also remove themselves in a single click by clicking on the unsubscribe link on the newsletter sent by us. Customers can also remove themselves by sending a mail with their email address and stating they would like be removed from our mailing list to Scuba.com, 1752 Langley Ave, Irvine 92614.

**Q: Is personal information shared with third parties?**  
**A:** Information is never shared or sold to any other party.

**Q: Can customers modify their personal information given?**  
**A:** Our customers can make changes to their personal information given on each order by logging in to their account.

**Q: What is your policy regarding credit card fraud (Safe Shopping Guarantee)?**  
**A:** Scuba.com asks for information only the card holder should know, at the time of purchase. Scuba.com then checks certain parts of this information to verify information is correct.

**Q: What methods of payment are accepted?**  
**A:** Cash (in our retail locations only), Check, Visa/MasterCard, American Express, Discover and Scuba.com gift certificates 

**Q: If an item is on backorder or out of stock, how are customers notified?**  
**A:** One of our certified instructors will call and/or email our customers to advise you an item is on backorder or is out of stock. Our instructors will also suggest a similar item in lieu of the item on backorder or out of stock.  Please note, email is not encrypted and is not considered a secure means of transmitting credit card numbers.  If you still have any concerns about ordering electronically, please call 1-800-34SCUBA to simply place your order over the phone. Have the item number, size and color ready for each item you wish to order. 

**Q: Why can't I add any item or more than one item to my cart?**  
**A:** Your browser must have cookies enabled to add items to your shopping cart. If your cookies are enabled and you still cannot add items to your cart then your shopping cart cookie has become corrupted and must be deleted. 

If you are unable to add more than one item to your shopping cart, then your shopping cart cookie has become corrupted and must be deleted. To delete the cookie, follow these steps: 

  * Internet Explorer 7.0: 
    * Go to: Tools > Internet Options > General Tab 
    * Click the Delete button under Browsing History 
    * Click the Delete cookies button in the pop up window and click yes on the prompt "Are you are sure" 
    * Click the Delete files button in the pop up window and click yes on the prompt "Are you are sure" 
    * Click the close button, then the OK button. 
    * Restart Internet Explorer and add an item. 
  * Internet Explorer 6.0: 
    * Go to: Tools > Internet Options > General Tab 
    * Click the Delete Cookies button. Click yes on the prompt "Delete all cookies" 
    * Click the close button, then the OK button. 
    * Restart Internet Explorer and add an item.
  * Firefox: 
    * Go to: Tools > Clear Private Data
    * Uncheck Everything but Cookies.
    * Click the Clear Private Data Now button
    * Restart Firefox and add an item.
